hello my friend I've got a personal
question for you today and that is how
old are you on the inside now before you
get offended that I'm asking people's
age I don't really care chronologically
how old are you I'm asking how mature
are you see I've met 55 year olds that
really on the inside they're 15 year
olds I mean the way they handle conflict
um the way that they actually conduct
themselves in business and and
Partnerships and they're just immature
they've got that selfishness that is a
part of growing up and I've met 15 year
old students
great discernment tough resilient
grace-filled inner Souls your age does
not predict your maturity level your
maturity level tells me your maturity
level how are you doing immaturity
what if for a minute you just thought
about your maturity level let's define
maturity maturity is the ability to
handle difficult situations with
emotional health I'll say that again
maturity is the ability to handle
difficult situations with emotional
health or another way we might Define
maturity is maturity is applying God's
truth when you don't feel like it
it's providing truth and Grace in the
moments when you really want to
overreact with selfishness and ego and
defense
this is a big issue with the Apostle
Paul he writes a lot about it to these
young mostly immature churches that he
starts one of my favorite places it has
Ephesians chapter four I'm gonna read a
little bit more scripture than we
normally do on the refill book but just
let this kind of sink into your soul
today as you get your day going so
Ephesians 4 11-16 here's Paul talking
about maturity so Christ himself gave
the apostles the prophets the
evangelists the pastors and the teachers
to equip his people for works of service
so that the body of Christ might be
built up until we all reach unity in the
faith and the knowledge of the Son of
God and become mature attaining to the
whole measure of the fullness of Christ
now we read this passage we think oh
this is like taking the Enneagram in my
pastor am I a teacher in my Apostle
that's not the meaning at all the
meaning of this passage is simply this
God gave the church lots of gifts so
you'll grow up
God gave pastors teachers prophets
Apostles why so that we become Unity
unified that's the sign of maturity and
that that we all be built up to grow up
God gave us lots of gifts where others
gets found in the church
verse 14 then once all those gifts get
into our life we will no longer be
infants tossed back and forth by the
waves and blown here and there by every
wind of teaching and by the cunning and
craftiness of people in their deceitful
scheming so the first idea is God gives
us a ton of gifts so we could become
mature the second idea is if we apply
those gifts consistently our life
becomes more stable
we're not tiles back and forth one of
the signs of mature life is they remain
stable they're not toused back and forth
so first of all you access the gifts at
church you apply them consistently and
your life will be stable is your life
stable right now
maybe you need to like get into really
get into church so that the gifts there
apply to you and then do that
consistently don't walk away when it's
hard don't stop during summer because
you got to go to Tahoe or this or that
get into those gifts that God provides
and watch that stability be built okay
one last thought I'll let you go for the
day instead of being tossed back and
forth speaking the truth and love we
will grow to become in every respect the
mature body of him who is the head that
is Christ from him the whole body joined
and held together by every supporting
ligament grows and builds itself up in
love as each part does its work so Paul
goes 360 here there's so much of this
passage I can't cover but just one big
thought he goes 360 here he goes God
gives all these gifts
you applying consistently and guess what
you become
you become one of the gifts
if you actually let those gifts that God
has given the church get into you you
become stable and then your position to
give your gifts in love
to other people in fact Paul says this
any church can grow any church can grow
no matter how difficult their
circumstance is if two things will
happen
number one people will practice their
gifts on each other and number two
they'll practice those gifts in love
are you letting the gifts that God has
given the church really get into your
life are you letting that happen
consistently are you seeing stability
from that
and are you turning around and sharing
those gifts with others if you do I
don't care if you're 15 or 55 you'll
grow in maturity you'll grow in
stability and you will be my friend a
wonderful gift to others
foreign